because Allah will ask you
about what
you say as Allah mentioned in
Surah
Al-Turk.
Don't say what you don't know
about.
If you don't know,
say, I don't know about it.
Similarly, when a learned
person is asked
a question of knowledge,
if he does not know,
he should say, I don't know.
La adil, la adil.
But when you don't know,
you say Allahu Ya'lamu.
Many of the scholars say,
no, don't say that.
If you don't know,
say la adil, la adil.
But if you know,
after full explanations and
all of these,
you cap it all up by saying
Allahu Ya'lamu,
by way of humbling yourself,
by way of affirming
that absolute knowledge of
every matter,
comprehensive knowledge of
having and encompassing
understanding of every matter
belongs to Allah,
then that is correct.
So, you can see that our Deen
Islam places a lot of
emphasis on
things we say.